<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-27T08:40:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">dizzy kitchen</title><subtitle>A fun cooking/recipies website</subtitle><author><name>Diana Zhang</name><email>contact@dizzydizzykitchen.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">banana goji bread</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/desserts/2019/01/21/banana-goji-bread/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="banana goji bread" /><published>2019-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/desserts/2019/01/21/banana-goji-bread</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/desserts/2019/01/21/banana-goji-bread/">&lt;p&gt;Banana bread is one of those healthy, unhealthy snacks. Its sweet and full of cinnamon flavor, but you’re also getting a small serving of fruit, which of course, makes everything healthy again. What makes a good banana bread is the texture. It should rise like cake, but still remain moist on the inside. I was suddenly inspired to make this recipe because of my friend Isabella and her mother’s AMAZING banana bread recipe. It was the night before I left for China. My closest Princeton friends threw me a going-away party and Isabella brought banana bread that her mother just mailed over. Let me tell you, midnight snacking amidst happy tears is probably one the best feelings in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recipe was probably one of the easiest ones to make. You basically just dump everything into a bowl, stir, shove it in an oven and hope everything works out. There are so many variations of banana bread. The world is your oyster; you can put anything you like in the batter. Chocolate chips is good choice (shoutout to Elaine for the idea) and I really like adding in walnuts for texture. Unfortunately, I didn’t have walnuts at home when I tried to make this, so I chose gogi berries instead. The texture of the berries when baked blends in with the bread, but it adds an almost bitter taste that nicely balances with the sweetness of the bananas. Plus, the red adds a nice pop of color doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all honesty, my final product wasn’t at all perfect, but it tasted marvelous! I just wish the batter could’ve rose a little more, so I adjusted the baking powder/baking soda ratio in the recipe. My oven is pretty atypical, so my baking process was a little complicated than what it should look like. Please try out this recipe when you get the chance. It’s perfect to bring to potlucks, share with friends, or just to snack by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Don’t forget to test if your bread is ready by using a toothpick to poke it. If it comes out clean, then its done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;840&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dWIJIbDUXyE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Diana Zhang</name><email>contact@dizzydizzykitchen.com</email></author><summary type="html">Banana bread is one of those healthy, unhealthy snacks. Its sweet and full of cinnamon flavor, but you’re also getting a small serving of fruit, which of course, makes everything healthy again. What makes a good banana bread is the texture. It should rise like cake, but still remain moist on the inside. I was suddenly inspired to make this recipe because of my friend Isabella and her mother’s AMAZING banana bread recipe. It was the night before I left for China. My closest Princeton friends threw me a going-away party and Isabella brought banana bread that her mother just mailed over. Let me tell you, midnight snacking amidst happy tears is probably one the best feelings in the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">apple pie</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/desserts/2019/01/21/apple-pie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="apple pie" /><published>2019-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/desserts/2019/01/21/apple-pie</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/desserts/2019/01/21/apple-pie/">&lt;p&gt;Apple pie, one of classic staples of Thanksgiving dinner. Bringing a feeling of warmth and holiday cheer, it is a must-have at the dinner table. What I made today is a slightly healthy versions of this delectable dish. Let’s start with the crust. we all know that apple pie has this beautiful golden buttery crush. News flash, butter isn’t exactly good for the arteries, so I’ve replaced the butter crust with an olive oil crust. After baking, the crust came out quite nice actually. It wasn’t as flakey as the classic crust, but it wasn’t as crumbly as a graham-cracker crust. All in all, would recommend for you guys to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also instead of sprinkling a ton of sugar on the apples to draw out moisture, I instead opted for some honey. It was a really nice alternative actually. The honey itself is quite sweet and fragrant, so it was a nice pairing with the tart, crisp apples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in theory, my pie was supposed to turn out to be super beautiful, but as you can see from the pictures, it was quite the opposite. It was a tragedy, I made my crust a little too thick for this one, so for those of you trying to make this, be careful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Butter is super expensive here in China, so I adapted my no-butter crust recipe from King Arthur Flour. Check it out here: https://www.kingarthurflour.com/recipes/no-roll-pie-crust-recipe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Yes, I know it took me two months to post, but I’m working on it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;840&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TvgwTQ0g_3A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Diana Zhang</name><email>contact@dizzydizzykitchen.com</email></author><summary type="html">Apple pie, one of classic staples of Thanksgiving dinner. Bringing a feeling of warmth and holiday cheer, it is a must-have at the dinner table. What I made today is a slightly healthy versions of this delectable dish. Let’s start with the crust. we all know that apple pie has this beautiful golden buttery crush. News flash, butter isn’t exactly good for the arteries, so I’ve replaced the butter crust with an olive oil crust. After baking, the crust came out quite nice actually. It wasn’t as flakey as the classic crust, but it wasn’t as crumbly as a graham-cracker crust. All in all, would recommend for you guys to try.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">sweet potato fries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sides/2018/10/15/sweet-potato-fries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="sweet potato fries" /><published>2018-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sides/2018/10/15/sweet-potato-fries</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sides/2018/10/15/sweet-potato-fries/">&lt;p&gt;Sweet potato fries has been the ultimate childhood favorite of mine. There was this shop basically walking distance from my house that sold boba and asian quick eats. I remember every time I went there, I would make a huge deal out of it. My favorite favorite favorite thing to order there was their sweet potato fries and crispy chicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I digress. This dish is super easy to make. It took no time at all and plus, it’s way healthier than having deep friend potatoes. Not only are sweet potatoes a good source of fiber, but they also very low in saturated fat and cholesterol. Basically they are root vegetable that are filled with nutrients, so you won’t feel guilty when consuming it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For next time, I would probably line my pan with aluminum foil or parchment paper. These will stick. Believe me, I learned that the hard way. I will also play with the flavors a little more by adding some garlic powder or paprika. Recently, my dad gifted me worcestershire pepper. I don’t know why, but I’m just not going to ask. Apparently, its some type of seasoning for barbecues, but I’m sure it will taste great with these sweet potatoes. I wanted to keep it simple for this round, but I will definitely spice it up next time. No pun intended!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;840&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_vSRM2PAn_I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Diana Zhang</name><email>contact@dizzydizzykitchen.com</email></author><summary type="html">Sweet potato fries has been the ultimate childhood favorite of mine. There was this shop basically walking distance from my house that sold boba and asian quick eats. I remember every time I went there, I would make a huge deal out of it. My favorite favorite favorite thing to order there was their sweet potato fries and crispy chicken.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">snow-skin mooncakes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/desserts/2018/10/07/snow-skin-mooncakes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="snow-skin mooncakes" /><published>2018-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/desserts/2018/10/07/snow-skin-mooncakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/desserts/2018/10/07/snow-skin-mooncakes/">&lt;p&gt;Eating mooncake during the Mid-Autumn Festival has always been a Chinese family tradition. The first mooncake appeared back in 1600 B.C. and regained its popularity in the second century Han Dynasty. Sharing resemblance with the celestial object (the moon), mooncakes nowadays have eight different variations, depending on where their origins are in China. One of the most popular fillings for mooncakes is the salted duck egg yolk. The most luxurious of the pastries will contain four egg yolks, each to represent a phase of the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular type of mooncake is famous to the Guangzhou area or at least the southern part of China. It’s not like the traditional mooncake thats baked and usually filled with some type of salted duck egg yolk. This mooncake, with the amount of glutinous flour used, almost takes like a Japanese mochi. And when frozen, mochi ice cream! Now who doesn’t love that? All in all, it’s sweet, subtly creamy, and just a wonderful treat to share with friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would I alter this for next time? Hmm… I want to explore the different flavors that I can make with this dish. I have made a separate attempt at making a matcha-skinned, ube-filled mooncake and not going to lie, that was pretty delicious too. Anyways, if you have the time, try out this recipe! It’s the Mid-Autumn Festival after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The snow-skin recipe was influenced by VictoriaBakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;840&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ewR_93hU9GA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Diana Zhang</name><email>contact@dizzydizzykitchen.com</email></author><summary type="html">Eating mooncake during the Mid-Autumn Festival has always been a Chinese family tradition. The first mooncake appeared back in 1600 B.C. and regained its popularity in the second century Han Dynasty. Sharing resemblance with the celestial object (the moon), mooncakes nowadays have eight different variations, depending on where their origins are in China. One of the most popular fillings for mooncakes is the salted duck egg yolk. The most luxurious of the pastries will contain four egg yolks, each to represent a phase of the moon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">boba milk tea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/drinks/2018/09/20/boba-milk-tea/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="boba milk tea" /><published>2018-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/drinks/2018/09/20/boba-milk-tea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/drinks/2018/09/20/boba-milk-tea/">&lt;p&gt;Boba milk tea was basically my entire childhood. I vividly remember in high school, we would create these lists that ranked the best boba shop to the worst. Even though it was so delicious, it can get a little expensive. With this recipe,
you can make a ton at a very low price. This treat super fun to make with family or with friends and because you are working with dough, don’t be afraid to play around and make your own shapes! Plus, hand-making the tapioca pearls is a good alternative because then you know exactly what you are putting in your body. There’s nothing processed, nothing faked. This is just about as natural as you can get with a drink like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this recipe, you can really make it your own. You can swap out the matcha powder for strawberry ice cream or mango puree. You can even try green tea instead of black tea. Using almond or cashew milk instead of regular milk is super delicious as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will I do better next time? My goal would probably be to make the boba way smaller. As you can from the video, I made some thicc balls, thicc enough I could barely get them up the straw. Oh well! We’re all still on a learning curve right? I’d also like to explore into the realm of Hong Kong milk teas. I recently came back from Hong Kong and apparently there is this super famous shop named Lan Fong Yuen on Hong Kong Island that will filter your tea through a woman’s stocking! Because its such a fine sieve, the tea will come out silky smooth. They also will add in some evaporated milk I believe. Stay tuned for a new recipe soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: I was so lost when making the boba, so the recipe is one I adapted from TaiwanCooking on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;840&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_3CYJfA_njQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Diana Zhang</name><email>contact@dizzydizzykitchen.com</email></author><summary type="html">Boba milk tea was basically my entire childhood. I vividly remember in high school, we would create these lists that ranked the best boba shop to the worst. Even though it was so delicious, it can get a little expensive. With this recipe, you can make a ton at a very low price. This treat super fun to make with family or with friends and because you are working with dough, don’t be afraid to play around and make your own shapes! Plus, hand-making the tapioca pearls is a good alternative because then you know exactly what you are putting in your body. There’s nothing processed, nothing faked. This is just about as natural as you can get with a drink like this.</summary></entry></feed>